AJDIN PIPO

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Full Stack Developer with a passion for creating web applications. My expertise lies mainly in backend development, but I also have experience in frontend development. Additionally, I hold a Bachelor's degree in Mechanical Engineering and I am currently pursuing a degree in Information Technology. In my free time, I am learning about Data Analytics and SDET.

DETAILS EMAIL ADDRESS

pipo.m.ajdin@gmail.com Kakanj, Bosnia and Herzegovina

PHONE WEBSITE

+38761602357 <u>www.ajdinpipo.vercel.app</u>

LINKS

GITHUB LINKEDIN CODEPEN

SKILLS

- Programming languages: JavaScript, Java, Python, TypeScript.
- Backend frameworks: Nest.js, Spring Boot, Django, FastAPI.
- Frontend frameworks: React.js, Next.js.
- Automation test tools: Selenium/Webdriver.
- Testing frameworks: TestNG, JUnit, NUnit.
- API testing: Postman API, Mockito, REST Assured.
- Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase.
- Source control: Github, Bitbucket.
- Test management tool: Jira.

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Kodecta d.o.o. | August 2023 - December 2023

Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina

Stack: Spring Boot, API Testing, React.js, MUI, Bitbucket

I worked on an e-banking app that uses a microservice architecture built in Spring Boot.

Mostly I worked on unit and integration testing using JUnit, Mockito, and Postman.

At a certain time, I worked on building an internal dashboard in which I used React.js, MUI, Axios, and Chart.js as the main stack. The main task of the dashboard is to show the status of each microservice, like internal and external services.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Kingdom Alliance d.o.o. | August 2019 - August 2020

Kakanj, Bosnia and Herzegovina

Stack: Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Android Studio, PHP7, React.js,

There were four projects I worked on. Two of them were enterprise apps for government and car assurance. And the other two were Android apps for news and municipality. The main stack was Spring MVC, Spring Boot, and Android Studio.

EDUCATION

ENGINEER OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Bachelor of information technology University of Sarajevo | 2020 - Present

MECHANICAL ENGINEER

Bachelor of mechanical engineering
International University Travnik | 2013 - 2017

PROJECTS

MOVIE APP

Stack: Next.js, Sass, Vercel, Public API (themoviedb.org).

Link: <u>DEMO</u> <u>SOURCE CODE</u>

This project is created to discover and explore different movies. It uses tools like Next.js and Sass to make the website look and work nicely. I used a database called themoviedb.org, to fetch and display movie data, including details, ratings, and trailers. And the project is deployed on Vercel.

PORTFOLIO

Stack: Next.js, Sass, Axios, Nodemailer, Firebase, Vercel.

Link: <u>DEMO</u> <u>SOURCE CODE</u>

This project is created in order to show my information, projects, skills, and the option to download my resume. It uses tools like Next.js and Sass to make it look and work nicely. I used a Firebase as a database to store and fetch images. Axios is used to fetch data such as images and information about projects. Vercel is used for deployment.

BOOKSTORE

Stack: Spring Boot 3, JPA, Spring Security with JWT, and Docker

Link: SOURCE CODE

This is a backend project that demonstrates how to build a RESTful web service for a bookstore using Spring Boot 3. To interact with databases and perform ORM I have used JPA, and PostgreSQL as a database. The project includes security using Spring Security with JWT. To connect with the database and run the app I use a docker-compose.

RENT A CAR

Stack: Nest.js, PostgreSQL, Prisma, Passport.js, Docker, Typescript

Link: <u>SOURCE CODE</u>

A backend project that demonstrates how to build a RESTful web service for renting a car using Nest.js and Typescript. I used PostgreSQL as a database and Prisma as ORM. Passport.js is used for security using JWT. To connect with the database I used a docker-compose.

For more projects, please visit my a GITHUB profile.